

# About Me

Software developer with a passion for computer graphics, currently in the Visual Effects industry and developing software tools to improve multiple aspects of the production pipeline. Proficient with a variety of Visual Effects software tools and their respective APIs, keen to apply production experience in a new development environment, with goals to expand knowledge of real-time graphics development. Previously experimented with GPU acceleration to improve interactivity within artist tools as part of academic study. Confident working under tight deadlines, and giving on-site support to production teams. Has a keen attention to detail, able to learn new codebases and APIs quickly, and adapt to their style and architecture. Adept problem solver with a good sense of humour, and enthusiasm to learn from peers. Interests in music, retro video games, and collecting plastic watches.

# **Experience**

## **Moving Picture Company (MPC Film)**

London, UK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

July 2018 - July 2020

- Working primarily on MPC's proprietary fur and feather grooming system, Furtility, initially as part of a small show support team and later as a
  dedicated cross-site product team.
- Collaborated on a redesign of Furtility's feather system, improving artist workflow and significantly reducing computation time for assets on shows such as Maleficent 2, amongst others.
- · Implemented a regression testing suite for Furtility, allowing for code changes to be validated against production assets.
- · Implemented a redesign of Furtility's internal caching algorithm, tailoring it to improve interactivity during grooming sessions.
- Working primarily with C++, Python, and Lua codebases.
- Experience working with Agile development methodologies.
- Screen credited on Maleficent: Mistress of Evil (2019), and Cats (2019).
- · References available upon request.

### **Moving Picture Company (MPC Film)**

London UK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

July 2017 - September 2017

- Worked for 2 months at their London studio as part of their 'First Step' internship programme.
- Assisted in the development of a dedicated grass spawning tool, investigating use of OpenVDB for sparse texturing.

# **Technical Skills**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Proficient with C/C++, Python.
- Familiar with Lua, Bash.

SOFTWARE APIS

- Familiar with Boost, OpenGL, and Qt APIs.
- Experience using various Visual Effects APIs, including Maya, Katana, Alembic, and RenderMan.

#### SOFTWARE

- Proficient using Git version control system.
- Familiar with development on using Linux systems.
- Familiar with various Visual Effects DCCs and renderers, including Maya, Katana, Houdini, and RenderMan.
- Experience configuring Jenkins CI/CD pipelines.
- Experience profiling and debugging using VTune and RenderDoc.
- Familiar with Doxygen for creating documentation.
- Familiar with LaTeX for creating academic reports.

# **Education**

### **Bournemouth University, UK**

B.A. Computer Visualisation & Animation, First-class honours

September 2015 - July 2018

- Studied the fundamentals of Computer Graphics techniques, Mathematics, and Computer Science.
- Relevant Modules: Principles of Rendering, Simulation Techniques.
- References from lecturers available upon request.

### **Midsomer Norton Sixth Form College**

A-LEVEL QUALIFICATIONS

September 2013 - September 2015

• Maths - A\*, Extended Project (Web Design) - A\*, Art - B, Photography - B, I.T. (AS) - C.

# **Norton Hill Secondary School**

GCSE QUALIFICATIONS

• Maths - A\*, Science - A\*/A, English - B/B, Art - A, Music - A\*, Graphics - C, German - A, I.T. - Pass, Philosophy - A.